<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Unihack</string>
    <string name="btn1">Relief</string>
    <string name="btn2">Hydrography</string>
    <string name="btn3">Conurbations</string>
    <string name="textRelief1">Formation of relief \nIn this lesson you will learn abut the relief units in Romania \n \nThe oldest relief unit is Dobrogea Plateau. It was formed during the Caledonian orogenes (Casimcei Plateau) and the Hercinica (Macin Mountains). \n \nThe Carpathians were formed by the rattling of the bark during alpine orogenesis. \n \nThe Subcarpathians were formed with the rise of the Carpathians, by the incrementing of the bark. \n \nHills and podiums have been formed more recently by depositing sediments brought by Carpathian rivers. \nThe exception is the Mehedinti Plateau, which was formed by the creasing of the crust and the Transylvanian Plateau, which was formed by sinking and gradually filling with sediments. \n \nThe plains were formed on the site of former large lakes or lakes, by sediment deposition. \n \nThe Danube Delta was formed on the site of a former Black Sea bay, by the action of three factors: The Danube with its alluviums, the small tide and the marine currents. \ngeology \n1. Eastern Carpathians \n \nNorth and Central groups: Volcanic rocks (andesite) in V; crystalline shale in C; flis (sedimentary rocks) in E \nSouthern group – made up of flis only \n \nMountains made up of limestone and conglomerates: Ceahlau, Hasmasul Mare, Ciucas \n \n2. Southern Carpathians \n \nComposed of crystalline systems, only at the extremities appear limestone and conglomerates \nLimestone and conglomerates appear in: Bucegi, Piatra Craiului, Cernei, Mehedinti \n \n3. Western Carpathians \n \nBanat group - limestone (karst relief), crystalline shale \n \nPoiana Rusca – crystalline systems and marble \n \nThe Apuseni Mountains – large variety of rocks (shale, limestone, granite) \n \n4. Subcarpathies \n \nFlis: Sandstone, marne, conglomerates \n \n5. The Poditions: \n \nMoldova, Transylvania, Getic,: Unbroken sedimentary rocks (strata are horizontal or slightly inclined): Sandstone, marne, gravel, clay \n \nDobrogea: Granite and basalt in Mt. The first is that of the first two \n \nMehedinti : crystalline systems, ironing \n \nThe West Hills: Uncut sedimentary rocks (sandstone, marne, clay), shale in Silvaniei Hills (in the “drowned” mountains) Prisnel and D.. Preluca) \n \n6 the plains: \n \nClay, sand, gravel, loess \n \n7. Danube Delta \n \nAlivion: Sand, gravel, banks \n \nThe Northern Group</string>
    <string name="textRelief2">Relief \n \nSpecific aspects \n- The maximum altitude is 2.3003 m in Mt. Rodna \n- Orientation of the peaks in the NV-SE direction \n- The glacial relief is present in the Rodna Mountains \nDivisions: \n- Mountains: Oas, Gutai, Tibles, Maramures, Rodnei, Obcinele Bucovinei; \n- Depressions: Maramures, Dornelor, Campulung, Oasului \n \nThe Central Group \n(Group Moldo-Transilvana) \n \nRelief \n \nSpecific aspects \n- The maximum altitude is 2,100 m in Mt. Călimani \n- Orientation of the peaks in the direction of NV-SE \nDivisions: \n- the mountains: Calimani, Gurghiu, Harghita, Ceahlau and Hasmasul Mare Stanisoarei, Bistrita, Persians, Baraolt, Bodoc \n- Depressions: Giurgeu, Ciuc, Comanesti \n \nSouthern group \n(Curvature group) \n \nRelief \n \nSpecific aspects \n- The maximum altitude is 1,954 m in Mt. Ciucas \n- Here the Carpathians bend, the mountain peaks are oriented ON THE NON-SV direction \nDivisions: \nThe mountains: Vrancei, Siriului, Întorsurii, Baiului, Bârsei \n- Brasov Depression – of tectonic origin, has altitudes of about 500 m, has a relief of hills.</string>
    <string name="textHydrography">The hydrography of Romania refers to all the waters on the territory of this country. Romania benefits from all types of aquatic units: Rivers and rivers, lakes, groundwater, marine waters..\nRomania’s hydrographic and hydrological peculiarities are mainly determined by the country’s geographical position in the temperate-continental climate area and the presence of the Carpathian arch..\nThe anthropogenic factor has contributed to some changes in these peculiarities..\n.\n-The flowing waters spring mostly from the central Carpathian crown and are collected almost entirely by the Danube. .\n-The rivers in western Romania are gathered by the Tisza which makes the northern border of the country a short distance..\n-Among its alfudents, more important are: Somesul, Crisul, which gathers the waters from a large part of the Apuseni Mountains, and Muresul..\n-In Banat, the main river is Timis, but navigable is only Bega..\n-The largest rivers in the south of the country are: Jiu, which crosses the two carboniferous basins, Petrosani and Rovinari-Motru; Olt, which sows the Carpathians in several gorge; Arges, which crosses Muntenia diagonally, and its tributary, Dambovita, passes through Bucharest; Ialomita, Which runs from west to east..\n-In the east of the country, Siret gathers large tributaries from the Carpathians (including Moldavia, Bistrita, Trotus, Buzau) and from the Moldavian Plateau (Bârlad), recording, near the Danube, the largest flow of inland rivers; Prut is the largest river in Romania, with a very high flow rate and a very long length..\nLectia 2 lacuri.\n-The lakes are found on all levels of relief and have very varied shapes, sizes and origins..\n-Although in large numbers (3500) are generally reduced in area (1.1% of the country\'s territory). .\n-The largest ones are those in the Razim lagoon system, or some sea limans (Tasaul, Siutghiol, Techirghiol), or river (Oltina Lake in southern Dobrogea, Snagov north of Bucharest)..\n-They are important as recreational and fishing grounds. Much smaller are the mountain lakes, some of glacial origin (Bucura), others of natural dam (Red Lake), or cantoned in volcanic craters (Saint Ana near Baile Tusnad, the only one of its kind)..\n-Numerous are also the reservoirs of hydropower interest (the lake at the Iron Gates on the Danube, the Spring of the Mountain on Bistrita, Vidraru on Arges, Vidra on Lotru, etc.) or for water supplies - on the valleys of Uzului, Doftanei, Firizei.</string>
    <string name="textConurbations">Bucharest is the largest city and also the capital of Romania.at the 2002 census, the city\'s population exceeded 1.9 million, while the Bucharest metropolitan area concentrates a population of about 2.2 million. In the future, plans are planned to expand the borders of the Bucharest metropolitan area..\nIn Romania, there are still five cities with a large population (around 300,000 inhabitants) and that are ranked among the most populous cities in the European Union. These are: Iasi, Cluj-Napoca, Timisoara, Constanta and Craiova. Other cities with a population exceeding 200,000 inhabitants are: Galați, Brasov and Ploiesti. There are also 11 other cities that concentrate more than 100,000 inhabitants..\n.\nCurrently, some of the largest cities are included in a metropolitan area (informal structures of collaboration between local authorities): Constanta (450,000 inhabitants), Brasov, Iasi (both with a population of about 400,000 people) and Oradea (260,000 inhabitants), while others are in the process of setting up: Brăila-Galați (600,000 inhabitants), Timisoara (400,000 inhabitants), Cluj-Napoca (400,000 inhabitants), Craiova (370,000 inhabitants), Bacău and Ploiesti.\nPlace	Name	County	Population.\n1	București	–	2.121.794.\n2	Iași	Iași	376.180.\n3	Timișoara	Timiș	329.003.\n4	Cluj-Napoca	Cluj	324.267.\n5	Constanța	Constanța	313.931.\n6	Galați	Galați	303.058.\n7	Craiova	Dolj	301.924.\n8	Brașov	Brașov	289.646.\n9	Ploiești	Prahova	228.550.\n10	Oradea	Bihor	221.398</string>
</resources>

